Elijah Newcombe

www.linkedin.com/in/Enewcombe30 07841 986892 enewcombe30@gmail.com

Profile

Front-End Web Developer qualified with an MTA qualification in C# Fundamentals, with 1 years' experience in Front-End Web Development using React.JS, TailwindCSS, Javascript, Typescript, Cypress and Node.JS. Presents ability to produce clean, maintainable and re-usable code. Looking to obtain an opportunity as a Junior Web Developer that will allow me to further develop my skills and continue training towards becoming a Full Stack Developer.

Hard Skills

Frontend	Languages	Frameworks	Source Control	UI / UX
HTML / CSS	Javascript / Typescript	React	Git	Figma

Core Skills

· Communication & Interpersonal Skills

· Collaboration & Team-Working

Problem Solving & Creativity

· Detail Orientation

- Organisation & Time Management
- · Adaptability & Versatility
- Accountability
- Self Motivation & Autonomous Learning

Projects

Project Jelly Bean

Browser based app that displays essential jelly bean information and company milestones. This project has been built using **React**, **Typescript** and **TailwindCSS** with data gathered from the jellybellywiki **API**. **GitHub** was used for version control and deployment (**GitHub Pages**)

Completed: October 2024

Website link: https://enewcombe30.github.io/jelly-bean/

GitHub link: https://github.com/enewcombe30/jelly-bean

Local Weather App

Browser based weather forecast that provides the user with 3 days of local weather data displayed as overall daily weather with an onClick to display hourly weather for each day. This app is built using **React**, **TypeScript** and **TailwindCSS** with data weather data gathered from the <u>weatherapi.com</u> **API** using the <u>opencagedata.com</u> **API** to assert user locale. GitHub was used for version control and deployment (GitHub Pages)

Completed: September 2024

Website link: https://enewcombe30.github.io/Local-Weather/

GitHub link: https://enewcombe30.github.io/Project-2-pair-game-2021/

Education

MTA C# Programming Fundaments - Pass 2021-2022

Online bootcamp provided by the Learning People focusing on **HTML**, **CSS** and **JavaScript** with introductions to multiple Web Tools and Frameworks.

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

C# Fundamentals

Audio & Music Technology - (incomplete)

2005-2007

Anglia Ruskin University

Completed 2 years of Audio Design and Technology with a focus on Studio Operations, Creative Music Software, and the Physics of Audio.

· Core Audio Skills

Studio Techniques

Live Sound

· Audio Mathematics

 Advanced Audio Technology Acoustics

Access to Learning CDT (Creative Design Technology) - Pass

2004-2005

Anglia Ruskin University

Achieved a Pass in the Anglia Ruskin University Access to Learning course which demonstrated a good understanding of basic principles associated with Audio & Music Technology.

Advanced Mathematics

Basic Programming

Graphic Design

Information Technology

Creative Writing

Audio Physics

Experience

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

December 2022 - November 2023

meetfern.ai

Junior Developer for a start-up company building Automation Software designed to provide Ad agencies IFTTT functionality when managing Amazon Sellers and Brands. Building and maintaining frontend code and Designing, building and maintaining unit and end-to-end tests.

- Building and maintaining React components focused on delivering clean and concise code to provide reusability.
- Designing, Building and Maintaining End-to-End tests using Cypress to identify broken code and prevent bugs reaching the production environment.
- Designing, Building and Maintaining Unit Tests to ensure helper functions are properly built and catch bugs in the code or data.
- Regular communication with dev team, designers and CEO to query potential problems and generate action plans to avoid delays in productivity.
- Building and Maintaining the apps landing page using Webflow inline with the designs at specified breakpoints.
- Using debugging tools and techniques when problem solving to efficiently identify and correct problematic functions and variables in the codebase.

Website - meetfern.ai

Cadence Audio, London, England

IT support for a High End Audio company Spearheading an Online Rebrand to tackle the loss of trade caused by COVID19 lockdowns. Maintaining a portfolio of 6 Wordpress websites including two e-commerce sites using WooCommerce and Bluepark.

- Maintaining Wordpress Websites Using wp-cli to Manage Plugins, Backups, Software Updates and adding New Products
- Managing all 301 Redirects to Retain SEO Placement when Migrating from Wordpress to eCommerce site.
- Managing Google Ads to Increase Traffic to sites focused on Raising Awareness to less Profitable Aspects of the Business.
- Designing and Building new websites to streamline online operations and improving User Interface to increase User Experience.
- · Delivering Site Analytics to Owner, CEOs and Directors to identify and address positive and negative aspects of online presence.
- Researched Company Product Portfolio to ensure correct Strengths and Specifications were represented accurately online.

2018-2021

Portfolio

- · audiolounge.co.uk Bluepark
- · audiolounge.in Woocommerce
- sme.co.uk Wordpress

- · loricraftaudio.co.uk Wordpress
- padood.com Wordpress
- · garrard.co.uk Wordpress

GENERAL MANAGER

City Pub Company, Cambridge, England

offered Site-Specific challenges.

General Manager of two sites within the group. Both venues provided unique Business Models and

- Successfully adapted the original Business Model to remain profitable while counteracting an 83% decrease in footfall after the first Covid-19 lockdown.
- Led Front of House team and provided On-Shift training to less experienced employees.
- Created and Implemented Managerial Protocols to track Sales, Wage Costs and Customer Feedback to Enhance Customer Experience during COVID-19 Restrictions.
- Managed time effectively and maintained duties to a high standard whilst learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- · Listened to Customer Feedback, Conducted Independent research and attended online seminars to further Product Knowledge and deliver the best offering to our customer base.
- Dynamically Managed and Problem Solved through Covid-19 restrictions to Maintain Business Viability while retaining a high level of Customer Satisfaction.

SENIOR MANAGER 2008-2018

La Raza Ltd, Cambridge, England

Starting as a Front of House team member and receiving many promotions prior to Overseeing Operations of multiple sites, an On-Site Bottled Cocktail Company and Off Site Events Business.

- Scheduled regular meetings with Site Managers, Suppliers and Student Bodies to ensure the business offered the best products available and Delivered on Customer Expectations.
- Executed and Showcased detailed quarterly Profit & Loss Reports with Site Managers preparatory to developing action plans and tracking success.
- Reported and Troubleshooted achievements and failings with the Business Owner and implementing changes by Coordinating with Site Managers and Teams.
- Collaborated with Local Law Enforcement, Licensing Authorities and Safer Nightlife Initiative Bodies to ensure Compliance across 3 sites each with their own unique Licensing Conditions
- Overseeing staff rotation across 3 venues to ensure adequate staff levels were on site during high trading times whilst adhering Wage Budgets.
- Working closely with Site Managers to Develop site specific events to drive business during times of lower levels of trade and Evaluate Successes and Shortcomings

Current Research & Interests

Node JS
GraphQL
arcGIS

RESTful APIs
Machine Learning
Python

References available on request